Guide to the Jonathan Solovy Oral Histories on Jewish American Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War ALBA.AUDIO.101
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jonathan Solovy Oral Histories on Jewish American Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War
1980-1981
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Solovy, Jonathan Stuart
ALBA.AUDIO.101
1.6 Linear Feet in 1 flat box, 1 card box, and 1 box
53 audiocassettes
Jonathan Solovy graduated from the University of Michigan in 1981. For his thesis on Jewish American volunteers in the Spanish Civil War, he conducted oral history interviews with Spanish Civil War veterans. The Jonathan Solovy Oral Histories on Jewish American Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War consist of oral history interviews conducted by Solovy with Jewish American volunteers from the Spanish Civil War. The interviews were conducted as research for Solovy's thesis "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War: a Study of Tripartite Identity".
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jonathan Solovy, "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War: a study of tripartite identity" (Masters Thesis, University of Michigan, 1981) (copy at Tamiment Library; DP269.47.A46 S65 1981a)
Fredericka Martin Papers (ALBA 1)
Scope and Content
The Jonathan Solovy Oral Histories on Jewish American Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War consist of oral history interviews conducted by Solovy with Jewish American volunteers from the Spanish Civil War. The interviews were conducted as research for Solovy's thesis "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War: a Study of Tripartite Identity". The collection consists of 53 audiocassettes and dates between 1980 and 1981.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers.
Biographical Note
Jonathan Solovy graduated from the University of Michigan in 1981. For his thesis on Jewish American volunteers in the Spanish Civil War, he conducted oral history interviews with Spanish Civil War veterans. His thesis is titled "Jewish American Volunteers and the Spanish Civil War: a Study of Tripartite Identity".
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access CDs for some audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only.
Some audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in alphabetical order by last name of the narrator.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University. The accession number associated with this collection is 2001.090.
Americans -- Spain -- History -- 20th century.; Audiocassettes.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, Jewish.
- Bessie, Alvah (tape 1 of 4), October 16, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-001)
- Bessie, Alvah (tape 2 of 4), October 16, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-002)
- Bessie, Alvah (tape 3 of 4), October 16, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-003)
- Bessie, Alvah (tape 4 of 4), October 16, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-004)
- Cohen, Milton, August 1, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-005)
- Fishman, Moe (tape 1 of 3), December 28 - 29, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-006)
- Fishman, Moe (tape 2 of 3), December 28 - 29, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-007)
- Fishman, Moe (tape 3 of 3), December 28 - 29, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-008)
- Gladnick, Robert (tape 1 of 4), November 3, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-009, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
- Gladnick, Robert (tape 2 of 4), November 3, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-010, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
- Gladnick, Robert (tape 3 of 4), November 3, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-011, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
- Gladnick, Robert (tape 4 of 4), November 3, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-012, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
- Harris, Sidney (tape 1 of 2), August 27, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-013)
- Harris, Sidney (tape 2 of 2), August 27, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-014)
- Hilkevitch, Aaron (tape 1 of 3), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-015)
- Hilkevitch, Aaron (tape 2 of 3), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-016)
- Hilkevitch, Aaron (tape 3 of 3), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-017)
- Lamb, Leonard (tape 1 of 3), October 26, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-018)
- Lamb, Leonard (tape 2 of 3), October 26, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-019)
- Lamb, Leonard (tape 3 of 3), October 26, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-020)
- Lending, Edward (tape 1 of 3), October 19, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 075, Cassette 101-021)
- Lending, Edward (tape 2 of 3), October 19, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-022)
- Lending, Edward (tape 3 of 3), October 19, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-023)
- Linn, Sidney, [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-024)
- Lossowski, Vincent (tape 1 of 3), November 15, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-025)
- Lossowski, Vincent (tape 2 of 3), November 15, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-026)
- Lossowski, Vincent ( tape 3 of 3), November 15, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-027)
- Osheroff, Abe (tape 1 of 2), September 29, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-028, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
- Osheroff, Abe (tape 2 of 2), September 29, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-029, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
- Pike, William (tape 1 of 2), April 2, 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-030)
- Pike, William (tape 2 of 2), April 2, 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-031)
- Prago, Albert, November 8, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-032)
- Rossen, John, May 3, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-033)
- Simon, John L. (tape 1 of 2), January 11, 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-034)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted.
- Simon, John L. (tape 2 of 2), January 11, 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-035)
- Stamm, Morris (tape 1 of 3), March 29, 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-036)
- Stamm, Morris (tape 2 of 3), March 29, 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-037)
- Stamm, Morris (tape 3 of 3), March 29, 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-038)
- Susman, William (tape 1 of 2), October 4, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-039)
- Susman, William (tape 2 of 2), October 4, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-040)
- Watt, George (tape 1 of 4), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-041, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
  Restricted
- Watt, George (tape 2 of 4), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-042, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
- Watt, George (tape 3 of 4), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-043, Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2)
- Watt, George (tape 4 of 4), [1980?] (Box ALBA Shared Access CD/DVD Box 2, Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-044)
- Wellman, Saul (tape 1 of 4), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-045)
- Wellman, Saul (tape 2 of 4), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-046)
- Wellman, Saul (tape 3 of 4), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-047)
- Wellman, Saul (tape 4 of 4), [1980?] (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-048)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 1 of 5), August 5, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-050)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 2 of 5), August 5, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-051)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 3 of 5), August 5, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-052)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 4 of 5), August 5, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-053)
- Zawadowski, Joseph (tape 5 of 5), August 5, 1980 (Box Shared Tamiment 076, Cassette 101-049)